

Ata Khalid Al-Emoush

CONTACT



+962 799887999



Anton.amosh@outlook.com



- USSR (Soviet), Ukraine



- Amman, Jordan



- Jordanian (24 Jul 1993)



www.linkedin.com/in/amosh-ata/



Ata AL-Emoush - Badges - Credly

EDUCATION

- Bachelor's degree || Computer Science Hashemite University 2011 -2015
- General Secondary Education Certificate
 Examination | (IT) Information Technology
 SJS Joseph Italian/Jordanian High School

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Working Under Pressure
- Excellent communication skills
- Leading execution
- Decision making skills
- Customer focus
- Adaptive to changing environments
- Problem solving
- Creating and Innovation
- Service Operations

SUMMARY

A Technology Enthusiast and Experienced Support Engineer (Tier 3). With proven ability to create and deliver solutions tied to business growth, organizational development, and systems/network optimization. Skilled problem identifier and troubleshooter comfortable managing systems, projects, and teams in a range of IT environments.

Expertise Area: Microsoft Azure, Microsoft 365, Active Directory AD, Azure Active Directory AAD, EMS, Microsoft Endpoint Manager, Azure AD Connect, DNS, DHCP, System Center Operations Manager SCOM, PRTG Network Monitor, Opsgenie, VMWare, Veritas Backup Exec, Fresh Service ITSM Ticketing System, Azure Advanced Threat Protection ATP, Privileged Password Manager for Enterprises, DUO Security, AWS, DataDog, Windows Server, SBCs, FreePBX.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Corporate IT Operations Specialist

Aramex | Amman (Global Support Office) KHBP | April 2019 - Present

Working at The Global Support Office, administrate various types of systems (Microsoft Enterprise and Multi-Cloud based) within a multinational Enterprise environment.

- Serving as the subject matter expert for Microsoft Office 365, including Exchange Online, Microsoft Teams, AzureAD Connect, AzureAD, Active Directory, DNS, DHCP and Group Policies Management.
- Skype and Office 365 migration and deployment.
- Experience administrating and supporting VMWare ESXi based servers throughout Aramex large and complex geographically distributed Data Centers. 20000 Users+
- Installing, troubleshooting, and configuring DNS, DHCP, Group Policy, Active Directory administration, and auditing event logs.
- Provide support to internal and external users within the service level agreement.
- Administrating and maintaining Aramex's Data Centers, backup, and Disaster Recovery process and life cycle.
- Manage Exchange Online users, manage recipients, create, modify, delete, shared mailboxes recover deleted emails and troubleshooting mail flow issues.
- Installing software, patching, upgrading and troubleshooting Windows server
 Operating systems.
- Local and remote IT support through all Aramex stations, Workstations Maintenance, hardware installation and handling Aramex's stock and IT asset orders.
- Aramex Network Operations NOC. Network Architecture, Planning, Implementing, Configuring, Troubleshooting and Testing of networking systems. Responsible for managing and maintaining the enterprise platforms SCOM, PRTG, DataDog, Dynatrace, and collaborating with Windows and Linux systems administrators, application administrators and developers, internal and external support teams, to determine requirements for thresholds, filters, events, alerts, and dashboards. Networks Experience with the escalation problems for Routing, Switching and WAN connectivity issues using ticketing system remedy.

ATA AL-EMOUSH

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PowerShell Scripting

Windows Server

Microsoft Azure

Microsoft 365

Network Operating Center

Azure Information Protection

Active Directory

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert MCSE Core Infrastructure
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Security
 Engineer Associate (AZ-500)
- Microsoft 365 Certified: Enterprise Administrator Expert
- MS-101 Microsoft 365 Mobility and Security
- MS 100 Microsoft 365 Identity and Services
- MS 700 Microsoft 365 Teams
 Administrator Certified
- MCSA Windows Server 2016
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA Routing and Switching)

LANGUAGES

- English
- Russian
- Arabic

INTERESTS

- Electronics
- Model building
- Video Gaming
- Mountain biking
- Travelling

Projects

- Contributed by moving on-prem exchange to Microsoft 365 cloud.
- Contributed to migrating Skype for Business (SfB) to Microsoft Teams (20000+ users).
- Created partnership with potential external enterprise partner Atlassian by deploying
- Opsgenie software to enhance monitoring and alarming on Aramex systems
- Onboarding and deploying System Center Operation Manager as a monitoring solution for Aramex Data Centers.
- Onboarding and deploying the PRTG monitoring tool as a solution for Aramex local stations.
- Automation of ITSM Fresh service (Ticketing System) with an Active Directory and Azure Active Directory using PowerShell.
- Automation of repetitive system administration tasks using PowerShell.
- Implemented the DUO authentication security on all terminal servers, as an extra security layer.
- Implemented the SSO for all newly onboarded systems through the Azure AD.
- Implemented centralized FreePBX monitoring for 80 Aramex stations which are distributed around the globe.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Flight Attendant

Royal Jordanian Airlines | Amman JO | March 2016 - May 2018

I had been working as one of the front liners of the Royal Jordanian company and had been responsible for the safety, security, and comfort of the guests onboard until they reach their destination by providing high-quality service, meeting the needs and demands of our guests with a comprehensive knowledge at performing pre-boarding security checks, flight and emergency procedures, the effective use of emergency equipment, on-board sales, effective first-aid and medical skills, good organizational and time management skills, and excellent hospitality.

- Communicated proficiently with all flight crew members and passengers.
- Cultivated language and communication skills through contact with people from around the world
- Learned to use body language and verbal communication to overcome communication and language barriers.
- Managed sales of inflight Duty-Free items (DFASS).
- Operated all mechanical and safety equipment with industry regulations and standards.
- Airport services, customer focus, communication, service operation, teamwork.